

Full Stack Web Developer

Summary

Former scientist turned Full Stack Developer with a strong foundation in applied science to investigate and preserve cultural heritage. 6 years in Biotech working on projects ranging from employing lasers to detecting explosives to using robots and 3D printers to manipulate bacteria to find solutions for a greener future. Looking forward to channeling my background and experience in the tech industry.

(Curious? Click for more)

	8	816 533 5557
	\times	filippo.20u@gmail.com
	in	/in/filippoventurini
to		/filippo20u
	9	https://filippo20u.netlify.app/

San Diego, CA (Remote)

Education

Coding Bootcamp LEARN Academy	MS, Chemistry San Diego State University
San Diego, CA, 2021	San Diego, CA, 2018
MS, Conservation Science and Technology for Cultural Heritage Università Ca' Foscari Venezia, Venice, Italy, 2013-2015 Unfinished, coursework completed.	BS , Technology for Cultural Heritage Conservation Università degli Studi di Firenze, Florence, Italy, 2010

Experience

Assistant Production Supervisor | (freelance)

(05/2021 - Present)

- Work closely with Production Manager and Producer from prep to wrap, ensuring all necessary documents obtained, review for completeness while following the Production company guidelines.
- Prepare and edit the Production Books following production and agency guidelines and utilizing the preferred platform, e.g.,
 Google Slides, PowerPoint, etc.
- Manage set Production Assistants to ensure production goals are reached while maintaining a collaborative and productive environment under pressure.
- Set up accommodation and travel and coordinate with local crew/ Production manager and vendors.
- Assist production companies with research materials and data management.

Full Stack Developer | Victorise, Carlsbad CA

(02/2021 - 04/2021), Internship

- Developing the new version of Victorise mobile app (React Native -NodeJS/MongoDB on AWS)
- Working with the developer team to migrate the frontend of the Victorise mobile app from Angular to React Native.
- Code optimization and bug fixing to improve performance and usability.

Full Stack Developer | LEARN Academy, San Diego CA

Bootcamp student (11/2020 - 03/2021)

- Completed 480+ hours of direct coding experience in an intensive web development Bootcamp.
- Gained proficiency in building JavaScript, Ruby, and React Applications.
- Practiced test-driven development to produce full-stack Ruby on Rails applications complete with databases (PostgreSQL, Active Record).
- Front-End experience with React.js, HTML5, CSS.
- Utilized effective communication and cooperation through pair and mob programming projects with teammates.

Scientific Consultant | Editech Art & Science

(10/2019 - present) (freelance)

- Prepare and edit technical reports for various research projects on works of art and non-destructive survey on historical buildings and archeological sites.
- Analyze and provide written summaries of experimental data.

Production Chemist | Abbott, San Diego, CA

(06/2020 - 10/2020) (contractor)

- Fermentation in bench-scale bioreactors of microorganism for production of antibodies.
- Preparation and operation of bioreactors through software interface and input data into laboratory data management system.
- Monitoring bioreactors through sampling and off-line measurements in a GMP environment.

Research Associate: Automation, High Throughput Screening | BP Biosciences Center, San Diego CA (10/2018 – 08/2019) (contractor)

- Research Associate in the automation department as part of an enzyme engineering project bridging the molecular biology and analytical chemistry groups.
- Data analysis and tracking with OC metrics and processing with Excel, LIMS (Benchling), and statistical software.
- Design and analysis of experiments based on analytical, fluorescent, or spectrophotometric outputs to improve enzymes for target characteristics

Quality Analyst/ Quality Control | BASF, San Diego CA (3/2018-10/2018) (contractor)

- Release testing, and stability testing for late-stage development and commercial products for BASF enzymes products.
- Analyzed results in a Good Laboratory Practices (GLP) setting and review results for compliance to specifications and reporting deviations.
- Prepare and revise SOPs and test methods. Managed data on analysis results and created concise electronic data reports for investigators and/or supervisor.

Scientific Consultant | Great Masters Art Science & Engineering, San Diego CA <u>/8/2015-1/2018</u>)

 GMAA uses the latest automation, imaging, and cloud computing technologies to disrupt how fine art is sold and valued, adding security to investors, and revolutionizing how the world explores art.

Technical Imaging Specialist/Analytical Chemist | Editech Art & Science, Florence, Italy (05/2010 – 01/2018)

- Analyzed more than 300 works of art from private collectors and museums combining techniques from chemistry and
 engineering. Preliminary analysis of art utilized multi-spectral imaging techniques (UV to X-rays) to optimize workflow and
 subsequent chemical analysis.
- Applied various imaging techniques (Laser Scanner, Thermography, and Ground Penetrating Radar) for inspection of structural issues, or conditions of historical buildings and archaeological sites not evident from visual inspection. Assisted with the dissemination of findings through written reports and oral presentations.

A cademic Experience

Graduate Research Assistant | San Diego State University, San Diego CA <u>(10/2015 - 09/2018)</u>

Teaching Assistant | San Diego State University, San Diego CA <u>(08/2015 – 05/2018)</u>

Research Associate | Università degli Studi di Firenze, Florence, Italy (08/2009 – 04/2010)

Skills:

Languages:

JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML5, CSS, SASS

Frameworks:

React.js, React Native, Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, Gatsby

Testing:

JEST, RSPEC, Enzyme

Other:

Git, Sourcetree, Bitbucket, Trello, XCode, Android Studio

Graphics and Design:

Adobe Photoshop, High-Res Photography, Multispectral imaging 3D Printing

Summary (long version)

Ciao,

My name is Filippo Venturini. I am a full stack developer based in Southern California. Born and raised in Italy, I developed a passion for science, particularly chemistry. I was also interested in art. A direct influence of growing up between Florence and Rome is the appreciation you gain for art and science.

After completing my undergraduate studies in STEM, I joined a company involved in applying engineering to art, architecture, and archeology. During my time there, I conducted research with structural and computer science engineers who developed software to improve the application of science to culture heritage. The results of this research were presented at the TED global in Edinburgh. Additionally, I was involved in several research projects developing and improving analytical instrumentation and seeking innovative ways to solve art related mysteries. All this work led to a National Geographic documentary and several books to establish methodology and disseminate findings.

With a desire to further my education and skills, I moved to the US to pursue graduate studies in Chemistry. My research in graduate school included working on a Department of Defense (DoD) funded study to use lasers in detecting explosives. I also worked on a project to improve instrumentation using emerging technology such as 3D printing. After earning my MS in Chemistry, I began working in the field of biotech using robots to automate experiments, at which time I became more curious about coding. I decided to leave the biotech field and pursue a career in the tech industry because I like to be challenged by solving new problems and to apply my critical thinking skills. I also like the idea that this field evolves rapidly, and you are continuously learning, growing, and you can reinvent yourself.

I have always been intrigued by computers and enjoy the challenge of mixing some creativity with science and logic. My ideal job setting is to work in a vibrant startup environment within a small team. Currently working on several projects to help promoting diversity and mental health and building technical skills in mobile development, React/React Native and crypto.

I would love to have a chance to chat with you and see if we can collaborate.

Filippo